Sreejith Balakrishnan, Ph.D. Candidate, National University of Singapore

Singapore, +6597262108, sreejithb@gmail.com

LINKS	Google Scholar, LinkedIn				
PROFILE	I am a Ph.D. candidate interested in developing Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning algorithms focus on value alignment, fairness, ethics, and safety. My current research topics include value alignments. Inverse Reinforcement Learning, and fairness in algorithmic decision making. In addition to my expanses a researcher, I also have an industry career of 8 years. I have held many positions during my career in Research Engineer at the Singapore Management University and Section Manager at ABB Private I	ent through perience as cluding			
RESEARCH INTERESTS	Value Alignment				
	Algorithmic Fairness				
	Inverse Reinforcement Learning				
	Learning from Demonstrations				
	Causal inference				
PUBLICATIONS					
Dec 2020	Sreejith Balakrishnan , Quoc Phong Nguyen, Bryan Kian Hsiang Low, and Harold Soh. Efficient Exploration of Reward Functions in Inverse Reinforcement Learning via Bayesian Optimization. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2020.				
Aug 2022	Sreejith Balakrishnan , Jianxin Bi, and Harold Soh. SCALES: From Fairness Principles to Constrained Decision-Making. Artificial Intelligence, Ethics, and Society (AIES) 2022.				
AWARDS					
Jan 2021	Research Achievement Award, National University of Singapore				
	Awarded for the NeurIPS 2020 accepted paper.				
Jan 2019	Honor List of Student Tutors, National University of Singapore				
	Awarded for outstanding tutoring for the module "AI Decision Making and Planning"				
Aug 2016 — Jul 2020	NUS Research Scholarship, National University of Singapore				
	Awarded to pursue Ph.D. program in School of Computing at National University of singapore.				
EDUCATION					
Aug 2016 — Present	Ph.D., National University of Singapore	Singapore			
	 Working on Inverse Reinforcement Learning and Value Alignment for robotics as well as Fairness in Decision Making. Relevant coursework: Uncertainty Modelling in AI, Advanced Topics in Artificial Intelligence 				
Aug 2010 — Jul 2013	Master of Science, National University of Singapore	Singapore			
	M.Sc in Electrical Engineering with a specialization in Computer Engineering				
	 4.6 GPA Relevant coursework: Real-time Systems, Linear Systems, Pattern Recognition, Evolutionary Computing 				
Aug 2004 — Jul 2008	Bachelor of Engineering, Nanyang Technological University	Singapore			
	 B.Eng in Electrical and Electronics Engineering with a Minor in Computing First Class Honors Relevant coursework: Robotics & Automation, Control Engineering Design, Modelling & Computer Vision 	ontrol,			

	Inverse Reinforcement Learning	Expert	Deep Learning	Expe	
SKILLS	Algorithmic Decision-making	Expert	Reinforcement Learning	Expe	
	Gaussian Process Regression	Expert	Active Learning	Experience	
	Bayesian Optimization	Expert	Evolutionary Algorithms	Skillf	
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY					
Aug 2017 — Dec 2017	Teaching Assistant, AI Planning and Decision Making, School of Computing, NUS, Singapore				
	 Conducted tutorials for the und Awarded Honor List of Student Received a high rating of 4.4 out 	Tutors			
Mar 2015 — Jul 2016	Research Engineer and Project Lead, School of Information Systems, SMU, Singapore				
	 Technical lead for a Singapore ur Engineering Corporate Lab (UN Modeled the passenger flow at va demand. 	iCEN).			
Jun 2008 — Feb 2015	Section Manager, Regional Aft Limited, Singapore	er Sales Supp	ort, ABB Private	Singapo	
	 Spearheaded a team of 5 enginee New Zealand. Invited to conduct advanced-leve around the globe. 		-		
PROJECTS					
Jun 2019 — Dec 2019	Decentralized Task Allocation for Multi-robot Systems, National University of Singapore				
Jun 2019 — Dec 2019		or Multi-rob	ot Systems, National		
Jun 2019 — Dec 2019			•	s with limited	
Jun 2019 — Dec 2019 Aug 2007 — Jul 2008	University of Singapore • Designed a task allocation algorit	hm for a decent Robot, Final	ralized multi-robot environments	s with limited	
	 University of Singapore Designed a task allocation algorit communication. Control System for Humanoid 	hm for a decent Robot, Final pore	ralized multi-robot environments Year Project, Nanyang		
Aug 2007 — Jul 2008	 University of Singapore Designed a task allocation algorite communication. Control System for Humanoid Technological University, Singating Interfaced a humanoid robot with 	hm for a decent Robot, Final pore h sensors using	ralized multi-robot environments Year Project, Nanyang various communication protocols		
	 University of Singapore Designed a task allocation algorite communication. Control System for Humanoid Technological University, Singating Interfaced a humanoid robot with I2C. 	hm for a decent Robot, Final pore h sensors using v Discovery Ce	ralized multi-robot environments Year Project, Nanyang various communication protocols nter, Singapore	s like Bluetooth and	
Aug 2007 — Jul 2008 Jul 2007 — Dec 2007 PROGRAMMING	 University of Singapore Designed a task allocation algorite communication. Control System for Humanoid Technological University, Singate Interfaced a humanoid robot with I2C. Humanoid Robot Exhibition, In the Led a team of 12 students to create synchronized against background 	hm for a decent Robot, Final pore h sensors using v Discovery Ce	ralized multi-robot environments Year Project, Nanyang various communication protocols nter, Singapore	s like Bluetooth and humanoid robots we	
Aug 2007 — Jul 2008	 University of Singapore Designed a task allocation algorite communication. Control System for Humanoid Technological University, Singate Interfaced a humanoid robot with I2C. Humanoid Robot Exhibition, Interfaced a team of 12 students to create synchronized against background. Python for High machine learning 	hm for a decent Robot, Final pore h sensors using Discovery Ce te a a public exhi	Year Project, Nanyang various communication protocols nter, Singapore bition where the movements of 4 Javascript for web	s like Bluetooth and	